For more information: https://dsevero.com

#### SHORT BIO

Graduate student with 5 terms of experience TAing, 3 years as a Data Scientist in Brazil, and 2 years as a Machine Learning Engineer implementing solutions in Py-Torch for healthcare applications. Vector Institute scholarship recipient. Research intern at Facebook AI Research (FAIR) working on lossless data compression.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Toronto

Electrical & Computer Engineering Doctor of Philosophy (M.A.Sc. to Ph.D. transfer) Started Fall 2020 Undergraduate Exchange Program (1 year)

# Federal University of Santa Catarina, Brazil

2010 - 2015

2013 - 2014

Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering First Class Honours, 99th percentile.

# **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

# Federal University of Santa Catarina

Teaching Assistant

# • Communications Theory

Fall and Winter 2015

Amplitude and frequency modulations; multiplexing; noise in communication systems; pulse modulation; analog-to-digital conversion; digital transmission in baseband and passband.

# • Introduction to Electronics

Fall and Winter 2013

Operational amplifiers; diodes; the bipolar junction transistor; field effect transistors; optoelectronic components.

# • Single-Variable Calculus

Fall 2010

Real-valued functions; limits; continuity; derivatives and applications; definite and indefinite integrals; integration techniques; improper integrals.

#### **CERTI** Foundation

2010 - 2013

Intern Programming Instructor

Responsible for the technical training of new and current interns. Created a training course in LabVIEW programming that is still in use as of 2021.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

Reys, Arthur D\*, Danilo Silva\*, Daniel Severo, et al. (2020). "Predicting Multiple ICD-10 Codes from Brazilian-Portuguese Clinical Notes". In: Intelligent Systems. Springer International Publishing, pp. 566–580.

Ruan, Yangjun\*, Karen Ullrich\*, Daniel Severo\*, et al. (2021). "Improving Lossless Compression Rates via Monte Carlo Bits-Back Coding". In: International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML).

Severo, Daniel, Elad Domanovitz, and Ashish Khisti (2021). "RCAQ: Regularized Classification-Aware Quantization". In: Biennial Symposium on Communications (BSC).

#### AWARDS

Vector Scholarship in Artificial Intelligence Recipient 2020-21 2020

The Vector Scholarship in AI supports the recruitment of top students to AI-related master's programs in Ontario and is valued at \$17,500.

https://vectorinstitute.ai/aimasters

<sup>\*</sup> Equal contribution

NSERC Applied Research Rapid Response to COVID-19 Grant 2020 Our project titled "Canadian Hospital Simulator For Management of COVID19 Cases and Contact Tracing" was awarded \$75,000.00.

https://www.nserc-crsng.gc.ca/Innovate-Innover/CCI-COVID\_eng.asp

# Virtual Design Challenge Winner

2019

Won 1st place at the VDC hosted by The University of British Columbia with my paper *Proof of Novelty*. Received a cash prize of \$3,000.

https://github.com/dsevero/Proof-of-Novelty

#### Student Merit Award and Medal

2015

Graduated with the highest GPA ever obtained (at the time) for my major. Elected "Best Student" by the faculty of Electrical & Electronics Engineering at the Federal University of Santa Catarina.

## Science Without Borders Scholarship

2013

Awarded a full scholarship that covered tuition, transportation, necessary materials and living costs to study 2 academic semesters at the University of Toronto.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Facebook AI Research (FAIR) Summer 2021 Research Intern

Independent Contractor 2018 - 2021

Machine Learning Engineer & Researcher

Linx Impulse 2016 - 2018

Head of Data Science

CERTI Foundation 2015 - 2016

Research Engineer

Wavetech Technology Solutions 2015

Engineering Intern

CERTI Foundation 2010 - 2013

Engineering Intern

WEG Industries Summers 2011 and 2012

Engineering Intern